AARON RAWLINS

Executive Security
Architect- Watson Health

9 Boulder, Colorado

(303) 709-4318

☑ iamwardie@gmail.com

in Linkedin linkedin.com/in/aaronrawlins/

Education and Certification

Colorado State University: Bachelor of Science,Computer Science

1999

Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)

2003

Information Systems Security Achitecture Professional (ISSAP)

2008

IBM Badges: Blockchain, Security and Privacy by Design

2018-2019

Awards and Volunteering

Promotion: 2015, 2014, 2008, 2008, 2001

Management Award: 2012

Delivery Awards: 2007, 2010

Board of Directors: Safe Shelter of St Vrain Valley 2008-2013

Housing and Human Services Board Member 2008-2012

Summary

Technological innovator and senior leader with twenty years global experience working with large multi-national corporations focusing on IT Security, Compliance, and Risk Management. Proven manager for security operations and compliance. Currently working at the forefront of technology integration, architecting, and creating the latest SaaS and PasS solutions on Cloud with the latest technology including Docker Containers, Kubernetes, and Micro Services delivery, as well transitioning legacy environments applications to hybrid and cloud technologies.

Work experience

2015 -Current

Executive Security Architect - Watson/Watson Health IBM Watson/Watson Health

- Authored Watson Health Security Policy 1.0 Based on Watson Security, IBM Security Policies, HIPAA Guidance, ISO, NIST.
- Authored Operations Process and Process Controls for IBM Watson Security- Including Patching, Incident/Change, Access controls, etc.
- Security Review Board Leadership- Security architecture review for cloud and traditional SaaS deliveries with experience in Docker containers, Kubernetes, and Micro Service delivery on Public, Private, and Hybrid Cloud for engagement, design and production offerings.
- Client Security Engagement- Direct client engagement for custom solutioning and architecture to meet Client Security needs for new services and cloud transformation.
- Risk and Vulnerability Management- Created Risk Process and documentation, reviewed and score risks. Tracked, approved and Closure of Risks. Brand Lead- Vulnerability Management for all Offerings.

2013 - 2015 Cloud Regulatory Compliance Officer

IBM Global Technology Services

- **Risk Assessments** Leading internal risk assessments across multiple organizations and delivery teams to identify risks and delivery gaps.
- **Process and Policy** Standardized a global framework, policies, processes, procedures, tools, and technology for delivery of IBM cloud solutions that require regulatory compliance.
- Sales/Solutioning Work with IBM brand teams to market new and innovative cloud solutions for our customers.
- Management and Leadership Manage internal IT delivery account teams that support all internal regulated cloud infrastructure.

2007 - 2013 Global Security Program Manager

IBM Global Technology Services

- Security Service Delivery Manage security operations at the enterprise level. Propose and oversee security architecture and delivery.
- **Identity Access Management** Responsible for enforcing and ensuring logical security policies, procedures, and tools.
- **Compliance** Perform security and audit gap analysis, create and drive remediation solutions to meet compliance needs.
- Risk Management Successfully built and maintained a program for risk management that included regulatory risks including HIPPA/PCI/SOX.
- Incident Management Act as management point of contact for all emergencies for both high level findings and environment instability.
- **Architecture** Final security review and approval for all architecture deployments in customer delivery solutions.

2001 - 2007 Lead Business Analyst - Security and Risk Management/MSSD Security Architect

IBM Global Technology Services